Chendi Li

looking for a 2022 Fall Ph.D. program

Linkedin.com/li-chendi

I am currently a graduate student at the State Key Laboratory of Computer Architecture, Institute of Computing Technology, Chinese Academy of Sciences (CARCH, ICT, CAS), supervised by Prof. Yunquan Zhang. My research interests including high-performance computing, optimized BLAS library, sparse matrix multiplication, CPU and GPU acceleration. Expected graduation date is 2022 Summer.

EDUCATION

Master of Computer Science, University of Chinese Academy of Sciences **Bachelor of Computer Science,** Hunan Agricultural University

Mon 2019 — June 2022

Sep 2014 — June 2018

RESEARCH EXPERIENCE

Graduate Student Research Assistant

September 2019 — Now

Institute of Computing Technology, Chinese Academy of Sciences

Beijing

Undergraduate Research Assistant

January 2018 — June 2019

Institute of Computing Technology, Chinese Academy of Sciences

Beijing

PUBLICATIONS

- 1. [IEEE ISPA 2021] Chendi Li, Haipeng Jia, Hang Cao, et al. AutoTSMM: An Auto-tuning Framework for Building High-Performance Tall-and-Skinny Matrix-Matrix Multiplication on CPUs.
- 2. [IEEE ICPADS 2021, under review] Jianyu Yao, Boqian Shi, Chunyang Xiang, Haipeng Jia, Chendi Li, et al. IAAT: An Input-Aware Adaptive Tuning framework for Small GEMM.
- 3. [CCF HPC China 2020] Chendi Li, Guangting Zhang, Haipeng Jia. Fast Computation of Elementary Functions on ARM Platforms(in Chinese)

RESEARCH PROJECTS

OpenBLAS, Contributor

Nov 2020 — Now

• OpenBLAS is an open-source BLAS library. I'm responsible for optimizing pre-pack matrix-matrix multiplication and triangular solve with multiple right-hand-sides(TRSM) on ARMv8 and X86 platforms.

Small-GEMM-JIT, Contributor

Jul 2021 - Now

• This is a just-in-time small GEMM framework targeting on CPUs. I help to launch the project and did many investigations on how to use JIT tools. I participated in the brainstorm and meeting every week. However, I'm not the main coder of Small-GEMM-JIT.

AutoTSMM, Author May 2021 — Jul 2021

• I designed AutoTSMM independently, which is used to build high-Performance tall-and-skinny matrix multiplication on all mainstream CPUs. And the performance is competitive with state-of-the-art TSMM implementation from Intel MKL and outperforms all conventional GEMM implementations on X86 and ARMv8 platforms. AutoTSMM was accepted by IEEE ISPA 2021.

IAAT, Contributor Nov 2020 — Sep 2021

• IAAT is an input-aware adaptive tuning framework for small GEMM. I'm not the main coder of IAAT, yet I participated in the brainstorm and meeting every week. IAAT is being reviewed by IEEE ICPADS 2021.

OpenVML, Co-author Jan 2020 — Oct 2020

• OpenVML is a vector math library. I'm responsible for optimizing the math functions on ARMv8 platform. The experimental results show that OpenVML achieve a performance improvement of 66% to 540% compared with C standard library function, and a performance improvement of 12% to 90% compared with Arm Performance Libraries(ARMPL). The paper "Fast Computation of Elementary Functions on ARM Platform" was accepted by HPC China 2020.

AutoFFT, Contributor

Jan 2018 — June 2019

• AutoFFT is a template-based FFT codes auto-generation framework for ARM and X86 CPUs. I'm mainly responsible for optimizing small-scale FFT on ARMv8 architecture. Later, I also did some preliminary work on multi-threading and 2D-FFT. AutoFFT is the first research project I participated in, and I learned a lot from it. AutoFFT was accepted by SC19.

TECHNICAL SKILLS

Tools Linux, Git, Vim, CMake, OpenMP, Pthreads

SkillsHigh Performance Computing, Parallel Programming **Programming/Scripting**C, Latex, Assembly, Python, JavaScript, Neon intrinsic